SR. PROJECT MANAGER IT Summary

Senior Project Manager bringing highly credible technical leadership to direct multi-functional project teams engaged in full system development and implementation in high tech environments. Experienced overseeing diverse teams of developers, analysts and quality professionals engaged in complex projects with budgets up to \$50Million. Solid understanding of project management tools. Project Management Professional and in Agile methodology. Always passionate and willing to learn new tools and technologies to support the team in delivering value to customers faster.

Skills

- Project goals and milestones
- Ouality Assurance
- Stakeholder relations
- Budget administration
- Risk mitigation planning
- Agile work processes
- Infrastructure planning
- Critical thinking and Troubleshooting
- Resource Planning and Capacity Management
- Reliable and trustworthy

Experience

Sr. Project Manager IT | 09/2019 - Current First Transit - San Bernardino , CA

- Implemented processes when issues arose to keep project moving forward and adjust to shifted priorities. Some of which include intake
 process, release management process and production support process
- Spearheaded key projects, resulting in high customer satisfaction and increased business revenues by working with technical and business teams in solutioning, and implementation
- Drafted action plans and led meetings with department executives to review project status and proposed changes
- Oversaw budgets for project, tracked expenses and timelines and communicated with key stakeholders on milestones
- Managed and tracked multiple projects and activities and lead the team in agile methodology by coaching them to transform and deliver faster
- Assessed project risks and devised mitigation strategies to avoid potential roadblocks

Sr. Programmer Analyst | 10/2017 - 09/2019 E-Business International - Princeton, NJ

- Tested functionality, performance and compliance of SOAP and REST APIs against design specifications to maintain strong development standards and high customer satisfaction
- Created and optimized automated testing tools for repetitive tasks using service automation tool CA DevTest and ReadyAPI
- \bullet Planned and implemented automated functional testing scripts with Selenium using cucumber and serenity framework, reducing labor hours by 60-80%
- Worked with Agile and Scrum methodologies to accomplish project milestones and meet demanding timelines
- Documented identified defects using HP ALM and Azure DevOps and helped developers complete further testing and resolve issues
- Resolved functional issues promptly by using technical and business process understanding, resulting in better productivity and improved workflows

Sr. Web Services Test Engineer | 02/2015 - 10/2017 Infinite Campus - Blaine, MN

- · Authored and maintained test cases and scripts for both manual and automated testing
- Investigated and reproduced defects and documented problems in HP ALM
- Conducted manual and automated tests in alignment with specifications and regulations using CA DevTest and ReadyAPI and reported results via email
- Performed root cause analysis of problems, documented faults in tracking system and generated daily reports
- Integrated Agile software delivery methodology into testing phases to expedite and enhance final product releases

Test Analyst | 10/2009 - 02/2015 Infosys Technologies - City, STATE

- Reviewed project requirements, created test scenarios and participated in testing of legacy system for update to new one
- Worked with off-site teams to complete timely tests and facilitate smooth product releases
- · Produced test scripts for new automated software testing rounds using HP UFT and VB Script
- Consulted with product owners and developers to fully understand intended features and functionality
- Tracked software bugs and detailed information regarding findings and resolution techniques in documentation for technical and business teams
- Augmented knowledge of HP UFT software and other quality assurance tools by actively participating in available trainings and workshops
- Created and optimized automated testing tools for repetitive tasks

Education and Training

Karunya University - City \mid Bachelors of Technology Bio-Informatics , 05/2009 Certifications

• Post Graduate Program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, University of Texas at Austin, May 2021

- Placed 1st in the Technical Category of American Airlines rapid coding challenge Hackwars 2018 and got the privilege to work with Master Card in New York for a 1 week of rapid prototyping exercise. Placed 1st at the Department Level Hackwars Cargo Hackathon 2019 for building a Chatbot on AACargo.com to enhance customer experience
- Received US Patent for Cargo Management System and Methods (CargoHero) app developed for tracking and notifying customers about their cargo shipments
- Was converted as FULL TIME employee at American Airlines within 18 months because of my exemplary performance then again offered
 the job to become a Sr. Project Manager IT in the next 18 months